

JASON A. DOLORSO



Data Scientist | Digital Transformation Strategist

□ jdolorso@yahoo.com +63 915 541 5368 in linkedin.com/in/jasondolorso/ jasondolorso.github.io/

GROWTH-FOCUSED DATA SCIENTIST with expertise on data mining, data engineering, machine learning, and deep learning algorithms. Able to quickly comprehend and learn new trends and methodologies; delivers consistently good results working with cross-functional teams and solving complex problems to drive value creation. Has developed digital transformation roadmaps for public and private companies, and innovation strategies for multinational conglomerates. Well versed in Python, SQL, Power BI, Tableau, and Amazon Web Services (AWS). Core competencies include:

- Machine Learning
- Deep Learning / Neural Networks
- Big Data / Cloud Computing
- Data Engineering

- Data Mining and Wrangling
- Data Visualization
- Interactive Web Applications
- Predictive Modeling
- Qualitative / Quantitative Research
- Innovation Management
- Digital Transformation
- Supply Chain Management

UNDERTAKEN PROJECTS

Beating the Philippine Stock Market

Machine Learning approach to portfolio management that utilizes Random Forest algorithm resulting in CAGR of 31% (vs PSEi: -2.8%) over 2016-2020 simulation.

CassavAI: Cassava Leaf Disease Detection using Neural Networks

Detection of four (4) types of cassava leaves disease using Convolutional Neural Networks resulting to 89.40% accuracy to mitigate losses and improve crop yield.

Improvement of Purchase Price Variance (PPV) Approval Process

Kaizen project to optimize critical approval process that mitigated risk of \$530M for a Fortune-500 company. Full data science portfolio at jasondolorso.github.io

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Emerson Electric Co. (NYSE:EMR) \mid Manila, Philippines **Data Analyst II – Supply Chain**

May 2018 - Feb 2020

- Drove Emerson's global supply chain by providing data analytics on logistics, S&OP, inventory, and procurement to enable data-driven decision making for the company's \$2.7 billion product line across all geo locations.
- Led the Quality Management System of the entire global supply chain department (115 headcount) to ensure the alignment of all processes, responsibilities, and documentations with the organization's core strategic direction; achieved 100% audit compliance.

 $\label{eq:philippine} \textbf{Philippine National Oil Corporation} \mid \mathsf{BGC}, \ \mathsf{Metro \ Manila}, \ \mathsf{Philippines} \\ \textbf{Engineering Trainee}$

Oct 2017 - Mar 2018

 Underwent training and assisted on designing solar power systems, strategizing multi-regional offshore exploration partnerships, and business planning for the country's LNG supply and terminals.

EDUCATION & CERTIFICATIONS

Master of Science in Data Science

Asian Institute of Management | Makati, Philippines | June 2021 currently pursuing, 3x Dean's Lister

Bachelor of Science in Petroleum Engineering

Palawan State University | Puerto Princesa, Palawan, Philippines | 2018 3x Dean's Lister

Certified Internal Quality Auditor | ISO 9001:2015 | 2019 Associate (Level 1) Certification | Global Innovation Management Institute | 2021